<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-06T07:26:28+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Elixir Conf EU</title><subtitle>Welcome to ElixirConf EU, co-organised by ElixirConf and Code Sync. ElixirConf EU is the premier Elixir conference in Europe, bringing the best speakers in the community together, for two days of first-rate Elixir talks and a day of tutorials.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Covid-19 safety guidelines</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/06/17/Covid-19-safety-guidelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Covid-19 safety guidelines" /><published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/06/17/Covid-19-safety-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/06/17/Covid-19-safety-guidelines/">&lt;p&gt;Your safety and the safety of others is of the utmost importance to us as organisers and The Hilton Warsaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before attending ElixirConf EU 2021 all attendees must complete and sign this waiver form via Whova app or on paper on the conference day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All attendees must present &lt;strong&gt;one of the following&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A negative COVID test dated no more than 72 hours prior to the conference (both quick test and PCR test are accepted)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of vaccination (either in writing, on a card, or on the mObywatel app - QR code)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer yes to all questions 3-7 in waiver form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not attend if you or anyone you have been in contact with has shown any symptoms of COVID 72 hours prior. If you click “Yes” on any item on the waiver form, you will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be admitted to the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who cannot attend in person can receive a full refund by contacting us up-to &lt;strong&gt;a month&lt;/strong&gt; before the conference or exchange the in-person ticket to a virtual one and receive the reimbursement of the difference in the tickets’ prices. If circumstances change and there is &lt;strong&gt;a legitimate legal reason&lt;/strong&gt; you are unable to travel to attend the conference, we will happily refund you right up until the day of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During the conference we will ensure that:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All attendees will have their temperature taken before admission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will limit how many attendees can be in one room following the guidelines from the Polish Health Authorities and the Hilton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There will be 1 meter between attendees and a seat will be blocked or moved apart between each delegate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attendees will be seated facing the same direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All attendees, speakers, crew and any additional staff need to wear a face mask inside the venue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sanitizers will be available on all tables and by all entrances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All doorknobs and all horizontal surfaces will be disinfected after each session&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All food and snacks will be served separately by the venue staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water served bottled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All rooms will be vented after each session&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Money back guarantee if we have to postpone the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="covid-19," /><category term="safety," /><category term="guidelines," /><category term="rules" /><summary type="html">Your safety and the safety of others is of the utmost importance to us as organisers and The Hilton Warsaw.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hybrid conference - what to expect? + Frequently Asked Auestions</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/05/10/Hybrid-conference-what-to-expect-&-FAQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hybrid conference - what to expect? + Frequently Asked Auestions" /><published>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/05/10/Hybrid%20conference%20-%20what%20to%20expect%20&amp;%20FAQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/05/10/Hybrid-conference-what-to-expect-&amp;-FAQ/">&lt;p&gt;September is coming close and though the pandemic situation is not yet fully contained, we’re optimistic to meet with you in Warsaw and we will make sure not only to deliver a great experience, but also that it’s delivered in a safe environment. However, we’re also keeping in mind that by then not everyone will be able to travel, therefore, we’ve decided to make ElixirConf EU a hybrid event, combining both an in-person and virtual conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be two different categories of tickets going on sale at the same time - for the in-person conference and training and for virtual conference attendance and separate virtual training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does a hybrid event mean?&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll be hosting a live event for those who are just as excited as us to attend in person at Hilton Warsaw Hotel and Convention Centre on 9-10 of September. There will be a mix of speakers attending in-person and streaming into the venue to help us create the right balance and atmosphere that you would expect from one of our events. The talks from the venue will be streamed to the virtual platform, accessible for those who attend online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I can’t attend in person?&lt;/strong&gt; To cater to people’s varying needs, we are continuing to offer this conference as a virtual event, live, on the same day as the in-person conference with talks streamed from the venue and given virtually. Over the last 12 months, we have developed a format for running virtual conferences that is full of learning, networking and social interaction. That will continue to be the cast for this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I purchase my ticket and my circumstances change?&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone who cannot attend in person can receive a full refund by contacting us up-to a month before the conference or exchange the in-person ticket to a virtual one and receive the reimbursement of the difference in the tickets’ prices. If circumstances change and there is a legitimate legal reason you are unable to travel to attend the conference, we will happily refund you right up until the day of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is the ElixirConf EU going hybrid?&lt;/strong&gt;
The pandemic regulations and state of coronavirus vaccinations vary across Europe. We know that not everybody, for a variety of reasons, will be able to travel and meet at big gatherings like ElixirConf. We decided on this format, not only to make the knowledge accessible to a wide audience, wherever they are based, but also to keep the community together and make sure we keep the high standards and diversity of the content (hence virtual speakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given COVID, why not go fully virtual?&lt;/strong&gt;
Whilst the situation is still fast moving, we believe that by September, the vaccine rollout throughout Europe will be sufficient to allow for events to be conducted safely. We will work with the venue to ensure participants have proof of a negative test or vaccination and to make sure the highest safety standards are in place. With these measures in place, we’re confident that we will be able to run a safe event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why attend the in-person event?&lt;/strong&gt;
For some of us, the social experience surrounding the conference is a big part of what makes them so special. While tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pK1hnGIR0EI&quot;&gt;Whova&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7O2AC4QHfX0&quot;&gt;Toucan&lt;/a&gt; lounge have helped us replicate a genuine social hallway track, the experience of exploring a new city and going out for dinner long into the evening is one that is better in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will the virtual content differ from the in-person content?&lt;/strong&gt;
The talks and their content will be the same for both the virtual and in-person conferences. We’re working with our technical partners to ensure the quality of livestreamed talks from the in-person venues look and feel similar to the talks at our virtual conferences so far. The slides and the speakers will both be clearly visible to ensure it’s easy for everyone to follow along at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does the price for the virtual event differ so much for the in-person conference?&lt;/strong&gt;
The price of the physical ticket includes the expense of hiring the venue and catering for lunches and breaks throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a virtual attendee, how will I be able to interact with speakers and other attendees?&lt;/strong&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pK1hnGIR0EI&quot;&gt;Whova app&lt;/a&gt; will be in use for both versions of the conference, allowing you to message other users and interact on the community board during breaks and on the talk’s chat during talks. The Q&amp;amp;A tab will allow you and in-person delegates to ask questions to speakers during presentations. To ensure there is still a dynamic networking feel at the conference, virtual attendees will have access to a virtual hallway room and will be able to talk to other attendees on camera. We will also schedule virtual sessions with exhibitors and sponsors for you to attend and be able to have a chat with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What time zones will be used?&lt;/strong&gt;
Virtual and in-person talks will take place at the same time on two tracks (9:00-17:00) in the Central European Summer Time zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I give a talk at this year’s event?&lt;/strong&gt;
Call for talks was open till 25th May and we’ve considered talks from speakers who can attend in person and those who would prefer to present from our virtual stage. If you missed the Call for Papers, as an attendee (with a ticket) you can submit a lightning talk. More information will be available closer to the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I submit to the in-person event will I be able to alter my choice?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, all ticket holders will be able to change from an in-person to virtual ticket up-to a month before the conference. We will also offer refunds and the ability to switch to a virtual ticket at any time should you be unable to travel for a genuine legal reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I submit to the virtual event will I be able to alter my choice?&lt;/strong&gt;
If you purchased a virtual ticket and you would like to exchange it to an in-person one closer to the event, you will have to ask for a refund (available up to 7 days before the conference for virtual tickets) and purchase the in-person ticket separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will the videos from the talks be public after the event?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, talks from this event will be published on our YouTube channel and website following the event, some videos will be kept exclusive to attendees who purchased a ticket for the first 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing an event worth celebrating with you later this year as we bring the community together, in person for a long overdue reunion. If you have any more questions, feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@elixirconf.eu&quot;&gt;info@elixirconf.eu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="hybrid," /><category term="virtual," /><category term="covid-19" /><summary type="html">September is coming close and though the pandemic situation is not yet fully contained, we’re optimistic to meet with you in Warsaw and we will make sure not only to deliver a great experience, but also that it’s delivered in a safe environment. However, we’re also keeping in mind that by then not everyone will be able to travel, therefore, we’ve decided to make ElixirConf EU a hybrid event, combining both an in-person and virtual conference.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exciting elixir frameworks from the june 2020 conference</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting-Elixir-Frameworks-from-the-June-2020-Conference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exciting elixir frameworks from the june 2020 conference" /><published>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting%20Elixir%20Frameworks%20from%20the%20June%202020%20Conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting-Elixir-Frameworks-from-the-June-2020-Conference/">&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting parts of any ElixirConf EU event is hearing from the creators or core teams of new Elixir frameworks. These frameworks open doors to the community and expand the capabilities of the ecosystem, making it easier for even more developers to do a wider array of tasks in Elixir. At our June edition, we heard first hand about the updates, capabilities and future plans for five exciting new frameworks. If you’re always looking for new projects or ways to expand your Elixir skill set, make sure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/#register&quot; title=&quot;tickets&quot;&gt;get tickets to our next edition of ElixirConf EU Virtual on October 7-8.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed the June event, you can catch up on the latest frameworks below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawly - Oleg Tarasenko&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big data is a growing area of interest and investment for businesses around the world. From machine learning to research, the ability to gather broad, reliable datasets is in high demand. Crawly, is a new Elixir framework that allows you to perform data scraping activities using Elixir. Hear from its creator, Oleg Tarasenko below. And, if that interests you, you can view a walkthrough of how to complete a task using crawly on the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/resources/webinars.html#how-to-use-web-scraping-in-elixir-to-gather-useful-data-erlang-solutions-webinar-58&quot;&gt; Erlang Solutions webinar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOC85IEKMsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scenic - Boyd Multerer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created by Boyd Multerer (the inventor of Xbox Live), the Scenic framework is a native graphic interface for Elixir. Scenic gives Elixir developers the ability to easily build applications that operate identically across all supported operating systems, including MacOS, Ubuntu, Nerves/Linux, and more. Scenic’s main focus is IoT devices but it can also be used to build portable applications. In his talk, Boyd looks to the future of Scenic and fills you in on changes you can look forward to in the upcoming updates. Learn more in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwMwMft2FP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lumen - Hans Elias Josephsen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lumen is the latest Elixir framework to improve the ease of use for front-end use cases. It is a new compiler and runtime suitable for any BEAM language that is compatible with WebAssembly. In this talk, Hans introduces the Lumen project with a specific focus on the compiler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kkA9rtMPyBs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membrane Framework - Marcin Lewandowski&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media processing requires a large amount of data, a huge variety of formats, protocols and standards. This has always made it challenging to work with. In this talk, Marcin Lewandowski, creator of the Membrane Elixir Framework, demonstrates how it can be used to process multimedia without headaches, using an example from media streaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJjrEaZZ72Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pelemay - Susumu Yamazaki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pelamay has been available since mid-May 2020. It can compile Enum.map in parallel with an integer and (or) a float calculation or String.replace into native code with SIMD instructions. The result is an increase in speed from Enum of between2.25x to 4.48x. In this talk, Susumu Yamazaki, Pelemay’s co-creator shows of what Pelemay can do with demonstrations as well as discussing something that we will see in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/00AECbsSK28&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If these talks have inspired you to discover more of the newest developments in the Elixir community, make sure you buy your ticket to ElixirConf EU Virtual in October. See the programme and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/&quot;&gt;buy your tickets here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="elixir," /><category term="frameworks" /><summary type="html">One of the most exciting parts of any ElixirConf EU event is hearing from the creators or core teams of new Elixir frameworks. These frameworks open doors to the community and expand the capabilities of the ecosystem, making it easier for even more developers to do a wider array of tasks in Elixir. At our June edition, we heard first hand about the updates, capabilities and future plans for five exciting new frameworks. If you’re always looking for new projects or ways to expand your Elixir skill set, make sure you get tickets to our next edition of ElixirConf EU Virtual on October 7-8.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2020 keynote highlights</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/28/2020-keynote-highlights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020 keynote highlights" /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/28/2020%20keynote%20highlights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/28/2020-keynote-highlights/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/elixirconf-eu-keynote-blog-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ElixirConf EU Virtual June 2020 Keynotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June 2020, we hosted our very first virtual ElixirConf EU event. ElixirConf EU has long been the premier Elixir users event in Europe. It provides a hub for like-minded community members to come together, share ideas, inspire each other, learn and ultimately, grow both the language and its community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was a great success with 400 members of the Elixir community attending. One of the surprising benefits of the virtual conference was that many Elixir users from other parts of the world had the opportunity to attend. This included Elixir programmers from Japan, U.S.A and even a keen attendee from Australia (where the event started at midnight local time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another unique feature of the event was the amount of live interaction with the speakers. As you’ll see in the keynote videos, our speakers provided valuable insights and interactions, answering the questions of our live attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who weren’t able to attend, the keynote videos are available on our YouTube channel, and this blog. We will also be releasing a selection of other talks exclusively via the blog in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, don’t miss out on our next virtual event in October. Purchasing a ticket guarantees you access to all talks, plus, live discussion and networking, job opportunities, exclusive sponsor giveaways and heaps more. Early bird tickets are on sale now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynotes from ElixirConf EU Virtual June 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris McCord: What’s new in LiveView&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phoenix LiveView is a game-changing framework for Elixir. Over the last 12 months, we’ve seen huge developments in its popularity and its adoption. For those of you new to Elixir, LiveView allows developers to create rich, real-time user experiences and web apps without requiring any JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his keynote talk at ElixirConf EU Virtual 2020 in June, Chris McCord, the creator of Phoenix LiveView, outlined the upcoming plans for both growth and improvement of the framework. This included plans to introduce deep change tracking and a view for LiveView to be giving users feedback by default to ensure that Phoenix LiveView is a good citizen on the web. Discover the full talk in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VU1JMg9AbLQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jane Walerud: Got a technical idea? How to build a company from there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jane Walerud is a serial tech entrepreneur with a connection to the BEAM community. She was pivotal in persuading Ericsson to release Erlang open source. Since then, she has invested in fifteen other companies, including Klarna (before incorporation), Tobii, Lensway and more. In her keynote at ElixirConf EU Virtual she shared her knowledge and insight into how to build a successful, financially viable company out of a technical idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an extremely interactive talk, with Jane leaving plenty of time for questions from our attendees, who asked a range of insightful questions. The result is a fabulous talk that is sure to help anyone thinking of turning their technical knowledge into a successful company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lqv9D54-0Bw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anna Neyzberg, Amos King and Chris Keathley: Elixir Outlaws live&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elixir Outlaws is an extremely popular Elixir podcast featuring three of the most respected members of the community. It is hosted by Amos King (CEO of Binary Noggin and Erlang Ecosystem Foundation member), Anna Neyzberg (co-founder of ElixirBridge) and Chris Keathley (Senior Engineer at Bleacher Report). The team made the most of the virtual conference format, using the opportunity to host a live podcast full of interaction from our global attendee list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9pRBhUB_9F0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these talks have inspired you to enjoy an upcoming ElixirConf event, then you should book your ticket to join us on October 7-8. We have a fantastic line up of speakers including Chris McCord, Linda Achieng’ Otieno, Sigu Magwa, Marlus Saraiva and heaps more. Get the full details on the home page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU Virtual </name></author><category term="keynote," /><category term="virtual," /><category term="2020" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Learn Elixir In 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why-learn-elixir-in-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Learn Elixir In 2020" /><published>2020-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why%20learn%20elixir%20in%202020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why-learn-elixir-in-2020/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/why-elixir.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/blog/why-elixir-is-the-programming-language-you-should-learn-in-2020.html&quot; title=&quot;why learn elixir&quot;&gt;Why Learn Elixir in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll show you how Elixir rates in relation to all of the above dot points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our consultant, Manuel Rubio, is a polyglot developer. Over the years working with Elm, Lua, Rust, Dart, Go, Kotlin, Scala, C, C++, Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Java, JavaScript, Erlang and Elixir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If he were to only pick one language to learn as a brand new developer in 2020, it would be Elixir and in this article he tells you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/blog/why-elixir-is-the-programming-language-you-should-learn-in-2020.html&quot; title=&quot;full article elixir&quot;&gt;READ THE FULL ARTICLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erlang Solutions</name></author><category term="elixir" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>