<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-05T09:23:18+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ElixirConf EU</title><subtitle>Welcome to ElixirConf EU, co-organised by ElixirConf and Code Sync. ElixirConf EU is the premier Elixir conference in Europe, bringing the best speakers in the community together, for two days of first-rate Elixir talks and a day of tutorials.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Come To London For Elixirconf Eu</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/03/16/Why-you-should-come-to-London-for-ElixirConf-EU/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Come To London For Elixirconf Eu" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/03/16/Why-you-should-come-to-London-for-ElixirConf-EU</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/03/16/Why-you-should-come-to-London-for-ElixirConf-EU/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-you-should-come-to-london-for-elixirconf-eu&quot;&gt;Why you should come to London for ElixirConf EU&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
London hosts one of the most engaging and varied tech communities in the world and you might be surprised to know that the UK also has a healthy, ever-expanding Elixir community. Some London-based companies whom you might not know that use Elixir include Duffel, Ably, Square Enix, British Broadcasting Corporation, SaltPay, V7, Vetspire and Nested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to our usual conference activities, we will also be hosting a &lt;strong&gt;special party&lt;/strong&gt; to celebrate ten incredible years of Elixir. We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that in mind, we are thrilled to be holding ElixirConf EU in London and we have a few tips and tricks for you to get the most out of your visit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coming-to-london&quot;&gt;Coming to London&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
London is open! From 4am Friday 18 March, all COVID-19 travel restrictions will be lifted, including the passenger locator form (PLF) and day 2 testing after arrival. That means you can plan, book and join us in London with ease and confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;affordable-accommodation&quot;&gt;Affordable Accommodation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking for the right place to stay on your trip to London? Check out some of our favourite accommodation options that might be more affordable than you’d expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/gb/the-wolfpack-inn.en-gb.html?aid=356980;label=gog235jc-1DCAMYAihQOLUCSAlYA2hQiAEBmAEJuAEHyAEN2AED6AEB-AECiAIBqAIDuAKwkr6QBsACAdICJDI2NzNjMWE2LWFmYzMtNDczMS1hMzdkLTM0ZDlmMzZlNmJlY9gCBOACAQ;sid=854e8c1ec848836e18992555eecbcfb1;all_sr_blocks=797674802_339969104_0_0_0;checkin=2022-06-09;checkout=2022-06-10;dist=0;group_adults=1;group_children=0;hapos=5;highlighted_blocks=797674802_339969104_0_0_0;hpos=5;matching_block_id=797674802_339969104_0_0_0;no_rooms=1;req_adults=1;req_children=0;room1=A;sb_price_type=total;sr_order=distance_from_search;sr_pri_blocks=797674802_339969104_0_0_0__12825;srepoch=1645185568;srpvid=6dfb544d105f0082;type=total;ucfs=1&amp;amp;#hotelTmpl&quot;&gt;The Wolfpack Inn&lt;/a&gt; is a nine-minute walk from the conference venue. This cosy little inn is perfect for a good night’s sleep or a quiet post-conference pint!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; Only an 11 minute walk away, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/gb/twentynevernsquare.en-gb.html?aid=356980;label=gog235jc-1DCAMYAihQOLUCSAlYA2hQiAEBmAEJuAEHyAEN2AED6AEB-AECiAIBqAIDuAKwkr6QBsACAdICJDI2NzNjMWE2LWFmYzMtNDczMS1hMzdkLTM0ZDlmMzZlNmJlY9gCBOACAQ;sid=854e8c1ec848836e18992555eecbcfb1;all_sr_blocks=4633_90863839_0_1_0;checkin=2022-06-09;checkout=2022-06-10;dist=0;group_adults=1;group_children=0;hapos=4;highlighted_blocks=4633_90863839_0_1_0;hpos=4;matching_block_id=4633_90863839_0_1_0;nflt=review_score%3D80;no_rooms=1;req_adults=1;req_children=0;room1=A;sb_price_type=total;sr_order=distance_from_search;sr_pri_blocks=4633_90863839_0_1_0__12906;srepoch=1645186490;srpvid=6dfb544d105f0082;type=total;ucfs=1&amp;amp;#hotelTmpl&quot;&gt;Twenty Nevern Square Hotel&lt;/a&gt; is a stunning little gem in the heart of Kensington overlooking the tranquil gardens of Nevern Square. The hotel is a beautifully restored Victorian townhouse boasting stylish and elegant individual private bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; Just 12 minutes from the venue is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/gb/oliverplazahotel.en-gb.html?aid=356980;label=gog235jc-1DCAMYAihQOLUCSAlYA2hQiAEBmAEJuAEHyAEN2AED6AEB-AECiAIBqAIDuAKwkr6QBsACAdICJDI2NzNjMWE2LWFmYzMtNDczMS1hMzdkLTM0ZDlmMzZlNmJlY9gCBOACAQ;sid=854e8c1ec848836e18992555eecbcfb1;all_sr_blocks=14254_88651888_0_0_0;checkin=2022-06-09;checkout=2022-06-10;dist=0;group_adults=1;group_children=0;hapos=5;highlighted_blocks=14254_88651888_0_0_0;hpos=5;matching_block_id=14254_88651888_0_0_0;nflt=review_score%3D80;no_rooms=1;req_adults=1;req_children=0;room1=A;sb_price_type=total;sr_order=distance_from_search;sr_pri_blocks=14254_88651888_0_0_0__14364;srepoch=1645186490;srpvid=6dfb544d105f0082;type=total;ucfs=1&amp;amp;#hotelTmpl&quot;&gt;Oliver Plaza Hotel&lt;/a&gt; with contemporary features and a new refurbishment. It’s a great option for those of you looking for more modern accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; If you don’t mind hopping on public transport and want to see more of the city, The Ibis styles &lt;a href=&quot;https://all.accor.com/hotel/7465/index.en.shtml&quot;&gt;London Southwark Near Borough Market&lt;/a&gt; is a quirky little hotel that draws its aesthetics from the vibrancy of its surroundings. A neighbour of the famous Borough Market, you can anticipate the tastiest food and drink options right on your doorstep at a price that won’t break the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fun-and-games&quot;&gt;Fun and Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
London has a rich historical past and a modern and vibrant multicultural scene. It’s also home to our headquarters in the East End near the heart of the tech community. We have compiled our local knowledge to bring you this list of fun spots to check out while you’re in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; London is home to some incredible outdoor food markets and June is one of the best months in the UK to explore them. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vinegaryard.london/&quot;&gt;Vinegar Yardto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mercatometropolitano.com/&quot;&gt;Mercato Metropolitano&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eataly.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Eataly&lt;/a&gt;, London has something for everyone’s taste buds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; Enjoy some of London’s incredible theatre performances. The west end boasts world-renowned theatre performances frequently featuring some of the world’s biggest names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; London has fun experiences and games that appeal to all audiences! Step into the world of VR at London’s own &lt;a href=&quot;https://feverup.com/m/109997?utm_source=secretldn&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_campaign=109997_lon&amp;amp;thm=159&amp;amp;utm_content=dopamine-land-waitlist&amp;amp;utm_term=cta3&amp;amp;cp_landing=cta-hero&amp;amp;_ga=2.237627011.284589723.1646212679-974343569.1646212679&quot;&gt;Dopamine Land&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; Did you know that some of London’s greatest attractions are all completely free? From world-class museums to stunning gardens and famous cultural landmarks, there is always something to see or do in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;world-class-food-and-drink&quot;&gt;World-Class Food and Drink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why not make the most of your time in London and treat yourself to some of the best culinary delights the world has to offer? London boasts some brilliant world-renowned chefs and Michelin star restaurants, however you don’t have to spend a lot of cash to get great quality food in London. Here are a few of our recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; For the high-end foodies out there, we’d recommend you check out internationally renowned chef and MasterChef Judge Marcus Wareing’s Michelin star restaurant, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marcusrestaurant.com/&quot;&gt;Marcus&lt;/a&gt;, just inside the Berkeley Hotel, across from the scenic Hyde Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; For our vegetarian and vegan attendees we would recommend you check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.holycarrot.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Holy Carrot&lt;/a&gt;, an exceptional vegan restaurant near London’s Hyde Park!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; You can’t come to the UK and not have a good plate of Fish and Chips! We suggest you check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goldenunion.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Golden Union&lt;/a&gt; in popular SOHO for what is arguably one of the best fish and chip restaurants in the city!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-you-in-london&quot;&gt;See You in London&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Without a doubt, London is the place to be this June! So &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/#register&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;secure your ticket for ElixirConf EU 2022 today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! Should you have any questions just drop us an email at info@codesync.global and our team will be on hand to help you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erlang Solutions</name></author><category term="traveling," /><category term="accommodation," /><category term="things-to-do" /><summary type="html">Why you should come to London for ElixirConf EU</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Want To Know More About Liveview</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/02/20/want-to-know-more-about-liveview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Want To Know More About Liveview" /><published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/02/20/want-to-know-more-about-liveview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/02/20/want-to-know-more-about-liveview/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;want-to-know-more-about-liveview&quot;&gt;Want to Know More About LiveView?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’ve got you covered. We’ve been singing from the LiveView hymn sheet for years now
and we’re pretty confident that you could become a LiveView evangelist too but first, here’s why we think it’s so great:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, LiveView is essentially an expansive library that lends itself to rich real-time user experiences with server-rendered HTML&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It offers a greatly simplified programming model when compared to JavaScript alternatives and LiveView-powered applications are stateful on the server with bidirectional communication through WebSockets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LiveView singlehandedly transcended what developers thought of Elixir worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, it set the path for moving Elixir from a server-side technology to the powerful full-stack ecosystem that it is today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without further ado here are some brilliant videos we’ve collected over the years from past ElixirConf events on Phoenix LiveView:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s new in LiveView - Chris McCord, ElixirConf EU Virtual 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VU1JMg9AbLQ&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In January 2020 LiveView saw rapid growth and a ton of new features added which creator Chris McCord takes you through one by one in his update on LiveView.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&amp;amp;A on LiveView - Chris McCord, ElixirConf EU Virtual 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rc_iqnZ05ZE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this next video, Chris McCord answers audience questions like ‘when you created Pheonix what was the problem you were trying to solve?’ and ‘where does surface fit in with the LiveView landscape?’ Check out the video for all his answers.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer games and collaborative editing with LiveView - Wiebe-Marten Wijnja, ElixirConf EU Virtual 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aErs_DIWxl8&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this talk, Wiebe-Marten Wijnja explains and shares his experiences on how Elixir, Phoenix and LiveView can be used to create web applications in which multiple users are collaborating in real-time-like collaborative document editing and multiplayer games.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoenix LiveView: Interactive Apps without Javascript - Chris McCord, ElixirConf EU 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8xJzHq8ru0M&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this talk, Chris McCord walks you through how to take advantage of the many features and functions of Phoenix LiveView. He also explains why there is ‘no need to write Javascript’ with Phoenix LiveView.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-miss-out-on-the-latest-liveview-updates-this-year-at-elixirconf-eu-2022&quot;&gt;Don’t Miss Out on The Latest LiveView Updates This Year at ElixirConf EU 2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You won’t want to miss our incredible speakers at this year’s ElixirConf EU. Our LiveView talks include: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/talks/introducing-livedata-liveview-for-json-endpoints/&quot;&gt;“Introducing LiveData: LiveView for JSON endpoints”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/talks/getting-to-phoenix-liveview-a-journey-through-nextjs-hasura-faunadb-supabase-rails-and-vanilla-phoenix/&quot;&gt;“Getting to Phoenix LiveView, A journey through NextJS, Hasura, FaunaDB, Supabase, Rails and Vanilla Phoenix”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/talks/building-a-block-based-editor-in-phoenix-live-view/&quot;&gt;“Building a block-based editor in Phoenix Live View”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/&quot;&gt;Early Bird tickets are on sale now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait before it’s too late, reserve your tickets today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="liveview," /><category term="phoenix" /><summary type="html">Want to Know More About LiveView? We’ve got you covered. We’ve been singing from the LiveView hymn sheet for years now and we’re pretty confident that you could become a LiveView evangelist too but first, here’s why we think it’s so great:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Covid-19 safety guidelines</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/12/03/Covid-19-safety-guidelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Covid-19 safety guidelines" /><published>2021-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/12/03/Covid-19-safety-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/12/03/Covid-19-safety-guidelines/">&lt;p&gt;Your safety and the safety of others is of the utmost importance to us as organisers and the ILEC Conference Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has now removed remaining domestic restrictions in England. There are still steps you can take to reduce the risk of catching and spreading COVID-19:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get vaccinated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider wearing a face covering in crowded, enclosed spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self-isolate if feeling unwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will ensure that:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we will limit how many attendees can be in one room following the guidelines from the UK Health Authorities and the ILEC, should the restrictions be reintroduced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;attendees will be seated facing the same direction during the talks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sanitisers will be available at the venue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we will provide money back guarantee if we have to postpone the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="covid-19," /><category term="safety," /><category term="guidelines," /><category term="rules" /><summary type="html">Your safety and the safety of others is of the utmost importance to us as organisers and the ILEC Conference Centre.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hybrid conference - what to expect? + Frequently Asked Questions</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/10/13/Hybrid-conference-what-to-expect-&-FAQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hybrid conference - what to expect? + Frequently Asked Questions" /><published>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/10/13/Hybrid%20conference%20-%20what%20to%20expect%20&amp;%20FAQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/10/13/Hybrid-conference-what-to-expect-&amp;-FAQ/">&lt;p&gt;June is coming close and though the pandemic situation is not yet fully contained, we’re optimistic to meet with you in London and we will make sure not only to deliver a great experience, but also that it’s delivered in a safe environment. However, we’re also keeping in mind that by then not everyone will be able to travel, therefore, we’ve decided to make ElixirConf EU a hybrid event, combining both an in-person and virtual conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be two different categories of tickets going on sale at the same time - for the in-person conference and training and for virtual conference attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does a hybrid event mean?&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll be hosting a live event for those who are just as excited as us to attend in person at the conference venue. There will be a mix of speakers attending in-person and streaming into the venue to help us create the right balance and atmosphere that you would expect from one of our events. The talks from the venue will be streamed to the virtual platform, accessible for those who attend online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I can’t attend in person?&lt;/strong&gt; To cater to people’s varying needs, we are continuing to offer this conference as a virtual event, live, on the same day as the in-person conference with talks streamed from the venue and given virtually. Over the last 18 months, we have developed a format for running virtual conferences that is full of learning, networking and social interaction. That will continue to be the cast for this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I purchase my ticket and my circumstances change?&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone who cannot attend in person can receive a full refund by contacting us up-to a month before the conference or exchange the in-person ticket to a virtual one and receive the reimbursement of the difference in the tickets’ prices. If circumstances change and there is a legitimate legal reason you are unable to travel to attend the conference, we will happily refund you right up until the day of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is the ElixirConf EU going hybrid?&lt;/strong&gt;
The pandemic regulations and state of coronavirus vaccinations vary across Europe. We know that not everybody, for a variety of reasons, will be able to travel and meet at big gatherings like ElixirConf. We decided on this format, not only to make the knowledge accessible to a wide audience, wherever they are based, but also to keep the community together and make sure we keep the high standards and diversity of the content (hence virtual speakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given COVID, why not go fully virtual?&lt;/strong&gt;
Whilst the situation is still fast moving, we believe that by June, the vaccine rollout throughout Europe will be sufficient to allow for events to be conducted safely. We will work with the venue to ensure participants have proof of a negative test or vaccination and to make sure the highest safety standards are in place. With these measures in place, we’re confident that we will be able to run a safe event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why attend the in-person event?&lt;/strong&gt;
For some of us, the social experience surrounding the conference is a big part of what makes them so special. While tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pK1hnGIR0EI&quot;&gt;Whova&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7O2AC4QHfX0&quot;&gt;Toucan&lt;/a&gt; lounge have helped us replicate a genuine social hallway track, the experience of exploring a new city and going out for dinner long into the evening is one that is better in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will the virtual content differ from the in-person content?&lt;/strong&gt;
The talks and their content will be the same for both the virtual and in-person conferences. We’re working with our technical partners to ensure the quality of live-streamed talks from the in-person venues look and feel similar to the talks at our virtual conferences so far. The slides and the speakers will both be clearly visible to ensure it’s easy for everyone to follow along at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does the price for the virtual event differ so much for the in-person conference?&lt;/strong&gt;
The price of the physical ticket includes the expense of hiring the venue and catering for lunches and breaks throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a virtual attendee, how will I be able to interact with speakers and other attendees?&lt;/strong&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pK1hnGIR0EI&quot;&gt;Whova app&lt;/a&gt; will be in use for both versions of the conference, allowing you to message other users and interact on the community board during breaks and on the talk’s chat during talks. The Q&amp;amp;A tab will allow you and in-person delegates to ask questions to speakers during presentations. To ensure there is still a dynamic networking feel at the conference, virtual attendees will have access to a virtual hallway room and will be able to talk to other attendees on camera. We will also schedule virtual sessions with exhibitors and sponsors for you to attend and be able to have a chat with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What time zones will be used?&lt;/strong&gt;
Virtual and in-person talks will take place at the same time on two tracks (9:00-17:00) in the British Summer Time zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I give a talk at this year’s event?&lt;/strong&gt;
Call for talks will be open according to the information on the website. We will consider talks from speakers who can attend in person and those who would prefer to present from our virtual stage. If you missed the Call for Papers, as an attendee (with a ticket) you can submit a lightning talk. More information will be available closer to the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I submit to the in-person event will I be able to alter my choice?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, all ticket holders will be able to change from an in-person to virtual ticket up-to a month before the conference. We will also offer refunds and the ability to switch to a virtual ticket at any time should you be unable to travel for a genuine legal reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I submit to the virtual event will I be able to alter my choice?&lt;/strong&gt;
If you purchased a virtual ticket and you would like to exchange it to an in-person one closer to the event, you will have to ask for a refund (available up to 7 days before the conference for virtual tickets) and purchase the in-person ticket separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will the videos from the talks be public after the event?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, talks from this event will be published on our YouTube channel and website following the event, some videos will be kept exclusive to attendees who purchased a ticket for the first 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing an event worth celebrating with you later this year as we bring the community together, in person for a long overdue reunion. If you have any more questions, feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@elixirconf.eu&quot;&gt;info@elixirconf.eu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="hybrid," /><category term="virtual," /><category term="covid-19" /><summary type="html">June is coming close and though the pandemic situation is not yet fully contained, we’re optimistic to meet with you in London and we will make sure not only to deliver a great experience, but also that it’s delivered in a safe environment. However, we’re also keeping in mind that by then not everyone will be able to travel, therefore, we’ve decided to make ElixirConf EU a hybrid event, combining both an in-person and virtual conference.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exciting elixir frameworks from the june 2020 conference</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting-Elixir-Frameworks-from-the-June-2020-Conference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exciting elixir frameworks from the june 2020 conference" /><published>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting%20Elixir%20Frameworks%20from%20the%20June%202020%20Conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/08/17/Exciting-Elixir-Frameworks-from-the-June-2020-Conference/">&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting parts of any ElixirConf EU event is hearing from the creators or core teams of new Elixir frameworks. These frameworks open doors to the community and expand the capabilities of the ecosystem, making it easier for even more developers to do a wider array of tasks in Elixir. At our June edition, we heard first hand about the updates, capabilities and future plans for five exciting new frameworks. If you’re always looking for new projects or ways to expand your Elixir skill set, make sure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/#register&quot; title=&quot;tickets&quot;&gt;get tickets to our next edition of ElixirConf EU Virtual on October 7-8.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed the June event, you can catch up on the latest frameworks below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawly - Oleg Tarasenko&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big data is a growing area of interest and investment for businesses around the world. From machine learning to research, the ability to gather broad, reliable datasets is in high demand. Crawly, is a new Elixir framework that allows you to perform data scraping activities using Elixir. Hear from its creator, Oleg Tarasenko below. And, if that interests you, you can view a walkthrough of how to complete a task using crawly on the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/resources/webinars.html#how-to-use-web-scraping-in-elixir-to-gather-useful-data-erlang-solutions-webinar-58&quot;&gt; Erlang Solutions webinar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOC85IEKMsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scenic - Boyd Multerer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created by Boyd Multerer (the inventor of Xbox Live), the Scenic framework is a native graphic interface for Elixir. Scenic gives Elixir developers the ability to easily build applications that operate identically across all supported operating systems, including MacOS, Ubuntu, Nerves/Linux, and more. Scenic’s main focus is IoT devices but it can also be used to build portable applications. In his talk, Boyd looks to the future of Scenic and fills you in on changes you can look forward to in the upcoming updates. Learn more in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwMwMft2FP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lumen - Hans Elias Josephsen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lumen is the latest Elixir framework to improve the ease of use for front-end use cases. It is a new compiler and runtime suitable for any BEAM language that is compatible with WebAssembly. In this talk, Hans introduces the Lumen project with a specific focus on the compiler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kkA9rtMPyBs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membrane Framework - Marcin Lewandowski&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media processing requires a large amount of data, a huge variety of formats, protocols and standards. This has always made it challenging to work with. In this talk, Marcin Lewandowski, creator of the Membrane Elixir Framework, demonstrates how it can be used to process multimedia without headaches, using an example from media streaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJjrEaZZ72Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pelemay - Susumu Yamazaki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pelamay has been available since mid-May 2020. It can compile Enum.map in parallel with an integer and (or) a float calculation or String.replace into native code with SIMD instructions. The result is an increase in speed from Enum of between2.25x to 4.48x. In this talk, Susumu Yamazaki, Pelemay’s co-creator shows of what Pelemay can do with demonstrations as well as discussing something that we will see in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/00AECbsSK28&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If these talks have inspired you to discover more of the newest developments in the Elixir community, make sure you buy your ticket to ElixirConf EU Virtual in October. See the programme and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elixirconf.eu/&quot;&gt;buy your tickets here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ElixirConf EU</name></author><category term="elixir," /><category term="frameworks" /><summary type="html">One of the most exciting parts of any ElixirConf EU event is hearing from the creators or core teams of new Elixir frameworks. These frameworks open doors to the community and expand the capabilities of the ecosystem, making it easier for even more developers to do a wider array of tasks in Elixir. At our June edition, we heard first hand about the updates, capabilities and future plans for five exciting new frameworks. If you’re always looking for new projects or ways to expand your Elixir skill set, make sure you get tickets to our next edition of ElixirConf EU Virtual on October 7-8.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Learn Elixir In 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why-learn-elixir-in-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Learn Elixir In 2020" /><published>2020-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why%20learn%20elixir%20in%202020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020/07/21/why-learn-elixir-in-2020/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/why-elixir.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/blog/why-elixir-is-the-programming-language-you-should-learn-in-2020.html&quot; title=&quot;why learn elixir&quot;&gt;Why Learn Elixir in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll show you how Elixir rates in relation to all of the above dot points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our consultant, Manuel Rubio, is a polyglot developer. Over the years working with Elm, Lua, Rust, Dart, Go, Kotlin, Scala, C, C++, Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Java, JavaScript, Erlang and Elixir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If he were to only pick one language to learn as a brand new developer in 2020, it would be Elixir and in this article he tells you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/blog/why-elixir-is-the-programming-language-you-should-learn-in-2020.html&quot; title=&quot;full article elixir&quot;&gt;READ THE FULL ARTICLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erlang Solutions</name></author><category term="elixir" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>